ASHTON HOLGATE

Front-End Web Developer

ashtonholgate.com - ashton.holgate@gmail.com - 07714 619 467



- PROFILE -

Enthusiastic and ambitious front end web developer with a passion for the web and a love of programming. Creative UX/UI Designer who loves creating beautiful and functional user experiences. Core competencies include React, Redux, Typescript, Javascript, and SCSS. Skilled user of Adobe Photoshop, XD, and Illustrator. Experience using Redux Selectors to keep data in Redux store as slim as possible and Redux Sagas to ease asynchronous data requests. Highly skilled at using animations in webapps to enhance aesthetics and increase app intuitiveness by communicating to the user the flow of data within the app.

- EXPERIENCE -

Luxtripper - Front End Developer & Lead Designer - July 2017 - Present

- · Redesigned and implemented key pages including hotel search, hotel landing, and bespoke itinerary pages
- · Designed and created internal sales and lead management system in React, Redux, and Typescript.
- Produced 'Luxtripper Style Guide' to help coordinate design efforts between developers and business

Gemini Design - Head of IT - July 2014 - July 2017

- Implemented and maintained all digital systems including email, cloud storage, shared calendar, task-management software, password management, quotation system, general folder structure protocol, and template-based website.
- Designed, created, and maintained complete Sketchup 'Dynamic Component' library which included a suite of objects that could be resized, and automatically redrawn, by SketchUp. Units utilized sketchup Animate feature wherever possible.

Personal Projects

• Designed and created <u>WhenWillYou.Win</u>, a lottery simulator made in **React**, **Redux**, and **Typescript**. Project exemplifies use of animation to communicate data flow throughout system.

- EDUCATION -

Essex University - BA(Hons) 2:1 Philosophy and Politics - 2010 - 2013

Transferable Skills

- **Creating** detailed critical analysis so as to generate effective solutions.
- Communicating intricate ideas in concise and easily understood ways.
- Producing articulate and professional documents within tight deadlines.

Education Summary

Philosophical education focused on communicating clearly, and persuasively, to present ideas convincingly through well-structured, systematic, arguments. Trained to have an eye for detail when problem solving and analysing new problems. Studied classical Greek philosophy, 17th century enlightenment ideology, and modern discourse on ethics, politics, and human rights. Organised presentation groups bi-weekly to identify, clarify, and expound upon key topics taught in previous weeks.

- SKILLS & INTERESTS -

- Musical Composition Keen piano player, self taught, who is currently exploring using FL Studio to produce digital content.
- Continual Self-Development Success today demands that one dedicates themselves to learning. With a growth mindset I have a passion for self-development and a willingness to never stop learning.